# James Smith

# IT professional with five years of experience in both first and second line roles

Swanwick

james\_work2013@live.com

07446 255023

I am an enthusiastic, self-motivated individual with a good range of experience and knowledge. I have been working within IT for the past five years and currently occupy the role of first\second line support at PCC Aerostructures UK with responsibility for three sites including the head office. I occupy a full UK driving licence and have access to my own vehicle. I'm confident when faced with new problems, projects and tasks and I will always push myself to achieve the highest quality of work. I'm always seeking to enhance my knowledge and progress my career further, be it through training courses, home learning, reading books or online forums. I love being challenged with something new as I feel this helps to develop me as a person whilst also improving my ability and skills within IT. I have excellent interpersonal skills and enjoy working in a team, I also have a strong capability to use my own initiative and ability to work independently to resolve issues. I am an excellent timekeeper with a good attendance record and always strive to do my very best in every situation.

# Work Experience

# IT Support 2nd\1st Line

PCC Aerostructures - Nottinghamshire February 2019 to Present

- Build and deploy new servers, virtual servers, workstations and mobile devices.
- Creating, Modifying and or deleting group policy objects.
- Patching servers and workstations to meet compliance regulations.
- Manage Microsoft active directory e.g. create new organisational units, groups and users.
- Creating PowerShell and or batch scripts.
- Providing both 1st and 2nd line support to users and colleagues across three sites both in person and remotely.
- Completing project work that has been assigned to myself.
- Ensuring backups have completed successfully and that the data is integral.

# 2nd Line Support Engineer

Synseal Extrusions Ltd - Nottinghamshire April 2018 to February 2019

- Build, deploy and manage both physical and virtual servers.
- Ensuring the backups of business critical data and servers have completed successfully and if necessary carrying out restores.
- · Creating, modifying or disabling group GPOs.
- Manage and or revoke SQL database permissions.
- Assist the 3rd line engineer with troubleshooting any SQL cluster issues.
- · Working on and completing projects that have been assigned or passed to myself.
- Working closely with the 3rd line engineer and other colleagues on business critical issues.
- Carrying out critical out of hours maintenance as and when is necessary.

• Travelling to sub-sites based in Huthwaite, Heage, Blackburn and Wigan in order to carry out tasks as required.

### **1st Line Support Engineer**

Synseal Extrusions Ltd - Nottinghamshire June 2015 to April 2018

- Create and or delete users, groups and organisational units within active directory.
- Create and/or delete new and existing exchange accounts, public folders and distribution groups.
- Importing new users into Microsoft Dynamics AX.
- Keeping the phone system up to date including creating and deleting DDIs.
- Setting up and deploying new computers and other hardware to end users.
- Installation of software packages to user PCs.

#### **IT Apprentice**

LB Plastics Ltd - Derbyshire June 2014 to June 2015

- Helped to assist the IT manager with any technical queries put forward by users.
- Carrying out printer maintenance on all site printers. This also involved the installation and setup of new printers.
- Assisting with the installation of basic software packages.
- Replacing or upgrading hardware components that have failed in user machines.
- Attending the Remit IT academy for classroom based training.

# IT Technician (Voluntary)

Tailor Made Computer Solutions - Derbyshire September 2013 to June 2014

- Build and supply customers including businesses with new computer systems.
- Performing re-installations of windows and ensuring the necessary data has been backed up.
- Software and Hardware troubleshooting to resolve problems with computers and completing any subsequent repairs.
- Taking telephone calls and dealing over the counter with customers in order to give advice and recommend options for dealing with their queries.

#### Education

# Diploma in Level 3 in ICT Professional Competence, Level 3 ICT Systems and Principles for IT Professionals

Remit IT Academy - Derby June 2014 to June 2015

#### **Diploma in ICT**

Derby College - Derby September 2013 to June 2014

#### GCSE in Design & Technology, ICT, Creative Media, Travel and Tourism

Swanwick Hall School - Derbyshire

September 2008 to June 2013

#### Skills

Active Directory (5 years), Exchange (5 years), Watchguard Firewalls (2 years), Netapp (2 years), Vmware (2 years), Microsoft SQL (1 year), Microsoft Office (5 years), HP Switches (3 years)

# Certifications/Licences

# **Microsoft 680 Configuring Windows 7**

June 2015 to Present

# CompTia A+ 220-801

October 2014 to October 2017

#### CompTia A+ 220-802

December 2014 to December 2017

#### **Microsoft Networking Fundamentals**

March 2015 to Present

# Additional Information

- Good knowledge and understanding of active directory and exchange.
- Good knowledge of server and workstation based operating systems.
- A good understanding of Watchguard Firewalls and security in general.
- Strong communication skills both on the phone and face to face.
- Experience with Watchgaurd and Ruckus access points.
- Experience with VMware, HyperV and Netapp devices.
- Experience with HP switches.
- Strong will and a drive to progress within IT.
- Some experience with deploying and managing SQL.